[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the antonym of 'contaminate'?",
    "options": [
      "sanctify",
      "invigorate",
      "taint",
      "purify"
    ],
    "answer": "purify"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What is the synonym of 'applaud'?",
    "options": [
      "Praise",
      "Criticize",
      "Denigrate",
      "Impress"
    ],
    "answer": "Praise"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "A synonym OF word 'Obscure' is",
    "options": [
      "Apparent",
      "Obvious",
      "Evident",
      "Dubious"
    ],
    "answer": "Dubious"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "A person who writes plays is called a —.",
    "options": [
      "play-write",
      "playwright",
      "plays write",
      "play'swright"
    ],
    "answer": "playwright"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Jamshed was unable to attend the meeting because he was feeling —.",
    "options": [
      "under the weather",
      "cats & dogs",
      "below the belt",
      "over the moon"
    ],
    "answer": "under the weather"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Which one is the correct spelling?",
    "options": [
      "Parenoia",
      "Peranoia",
      "Paranoia",
      "Paranua"
    ],
    "answer": "Paranoia"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "The scientists are going to _ a study on the effects of sound pollution on young children.",
    "options": [
      "carry out",
      "carry in",
      "carry with",
      "carry for"
    ],
    "answer": "carry out"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "The teacher took him to task means, the teacher",
    "options": [
      "reprimanded him",
      "praised him",
      "threatened him",
      "promoted him"
    ],
    "answer": "reprimanded him"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "As far as I'm concerned, all he's good _ is making up the most improbable excuses anyone has ever heard.",
    "options": [
      "with",
      "on",
      "in",
      "at"
    ],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The little boy does whatever his mother",
    "options": [
      "have done",
      "were doing",
      "does",
      "done"
    ],
    "answer": "does"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "I _ for you for the last three months.",
    "options": [
      "am worked",
      "have been working",
      "will work",
      "will have worked"
    ],
    "answer": "have been working"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "What is the verb form of 'ability'?",
    "options": [
      "Able",
      "Ably",
      "Enable",
      "Ableness"
    ],
    "answer": "Enable"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Reading as a hobby is on the wane; people hardly read newspaper, _ books.",
    "options": [
      "would rather",
      "had better",
      "let alone",
      "as if"
    ],
    "answer": "let alone"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "The solution that the engineer provided _.",
    "options": [
      "was not correct but also complicated",
      "was correct but complicated",
      "correct only but complicated",
      "not only correct but complicated"
    ],
    "answer": "was correct but complicated"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "No matter how hard I tried to make them understand, they just wouldn't take my word for _ I said, _ annoyed me very much.",
    "options": [
      "that/that",
      "that/which",
      "what/which",
      "which/ which"
    ],
    "answer": "what/which"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "They never gave a thought to probable future problems when the plans _ five years ago.",
    "options": [
      "to be laid down",
      "have laid down",
      "were being laid down",
      "had been laid down"
    ],
    "answer": "were being laid down"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "I was under the impression that you, too, _ along with us.",
    "options": [
      "was supposed to come",
      "were supposed to come",
      "have supposed to come",
      "are supposed to come"
    ],
    "answer": "were supposed to come"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "_, Rahim went to collect his payment.",
    "options": [
      "Although he had completed his work successfully",
      "Although the work has completed",
      "having completed his work successfully",
      "As long as the work is completed with success"
    ],
    "answer": "having completed his work successfully"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "I _ me what happened",
    "options": [
      "would like that tell",
      "would like for telling",
      "would like that you tell",
      "would like you for tell"
    ],
    "answer": "would like that you tell"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "It was _ that Mina couldn't finish it alone.",
    "options": [
      "difficult job",
      "such a difficult job",
      "such difficult a job",
      "very difficult a job"
    ],
    "answer": "such a difficult job"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Which of the following sentences is correct?",
    "options": [
      "They treated him like a King when he won the lottery.",
      "They treated him as being a King when he won the lottery.",
      "They treated him a King when he won the lottery.",
      "They treated him as if a King when he won the lottery."
    ],
    "answer": "They treated him like a King when he won the lottery."
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "The thickness of the mats _.",
    "options": [
      "vary",
      "varies",
      "have varied",
      "were variable"
    ],
    "answer": "vary"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "Which one is correct?",
    "options": [
      "This is the man in which I have no confidence.",
      "This is the man who I have no confidence.",
      "This is the man in whom I have no confidence.",
      "This is the man whom I have no confidence."
    ],
    "answer": "This is the man in whom I have no confidence."
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The correct passive form of the sentence, 'Who has created this mess?'",
    "options": [
      "Who has been created this mess?",
      "By whom is this mess created?",
      "By whom has this mess been created?",
      "By whom this mess is created?"
    ],
    "answer": "By whom has this mess been created?"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "This box is very heavy, _ me a hand?",
    "options": [
      "would you mind giving",
      "will you mind give",
      "are you mind giving",
      "do you mind give"
    ],
    "answer": "would you mind giving"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the synonym of \"incipient\"?",
    "options": [
      "hazy",
      "Inadequate",
      "Developing",
      "Resistant"
    ],
    "answer": "Developing"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "What is the antonym of \"transience\"?",
    "options": [
      "Permanence",
      "Deception",
      "Instability",
      "Fluctuation"
    ],
    "answer": "Permanence"
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "The phrase 'Achilles' heel' means:",
    "options": [
      "Strength",
      "Weakness",
      "Courage",
      "Vital point"
    ],
    "answer": "Weakness"
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "'Spill the beans' means—",
    "options": [
      "destroy something",
      "Reveal a secret",
      "make a mess",
      "Drop something accidentally"
    ],
    "answer": "Reveal a secret"
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "To read between the lines' means—",
    "options": [
      "read rapidly",
      "look for hiding meaning",
      "read very quickly",
      "memorize a passage"
    ],
    "answer": "look for hiding meaning"
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "Circular শব্দের বাংলা পরিভাষিক রূপ -",
    "options": [
      "প্রজ্ঞাপন",
      "প্রত্যয়ন",
      "বিজ্ঞপ্তি",
      "পরিপত্র"
    ],
    "answer": "পরিপত্র"
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Which one is the correct spelling?",
    "options": [
      "Consciencious",
      "Conscientious",
      "Consencious",
      "Concietious"
    ],
    "answer": "Conscientious"
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "She is skilled ------- negotiation complex contracts.",
    "options": [
      "at",
      "for",
      "on",
      "with"
    ],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "He vowed to ___ his father's death.",
    "options": [
      "revenge",
      "avenge",
      "take revenge",
      "avenge for"
    ],
    "answer": "avenge"
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "\"If you want the job, you need to strike while the iron is hot\" means",
    "options": [
      "You need to complain to the supervisor",
      "You need to decide what you want to become in life",
      "You need to keep preparing for the job",
      "You need to act quickly while the opportunity is still available."
    ],
    "answer": "You need to act quickly while the opportunity is still available."
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "What is the antonym of the word 'indifferent'?",
    "options": [
      "dissimilar",
      "apathetic",
      "different",
      "caring"
    ],
    "answer": "caring"
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "Choose the correct spelling.",
    "options": [
      "dissemination",
      "dissasemination",
      "disemination",
      "dissemination"
    ],
    "answer": "dissemination"
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "What is the meaning of the word 'suffrage'?",
    "options": [
      "fundamental right",
      "right to vote",
      "freedom of press",
      "sufferings of people"
    ],
    "answer": "right to vote"
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "A.K Fazlul Haque was the 'Tiger of Bengal'. The sentence is an example of an/an __.",
    "options": [
      "simile",
      "metaphor",
      "allusion",
      "personification"
    ],
    "answer": "metaphor"
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "Which of the following options is the closest in meaning to the sentence, \"He enjoyed himself immensely at the party\".",
    "options": [
      "He had a horrible time at the party.",
      "He had a terrible time at the party.",
      "He had a terrific time at the party.",
      "He had a terrifying time at the party."
    ],
    "answer": "He had a terrific time at the party."
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "The scouts in my school were sure to visit the flooded town, the condition ___ was not known.",
    "options": [
      "in which",
      "whose",
      "that",
      "of which"
    ],
    "answer": "of which"
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "I ___ newspapers every day.",
    "options": [
      "used to reading",
      "use to read",
      "am used to reading",
      "am used to read"
    ],
    "answer": "am used to reading"
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "I wish I ___ all the questions correctly.",
    "options": [
      "answer",
      "answered",
      "will answer",
      "have answered"
    ],
    "answer": "answered"
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "I cannot hear what you ___ because everybody is talking so loudly.",
    "options": [
      "said",
      "saying",
      "will be saying",
      "are saying"
    ],
    "answer": "are saying"
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "Three-fourths of the Earth's surface ___ water.",
    "options": [
      "are covered by",
      "covers by",
      "is covered by",
      "have been covered by"
    ],
    "answer": "is covered by"
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Would you mind ___ me your pen?",
    "options": [
      "in lending",
      "lending",
      "borrowing",
      "lend"
    ],
    "answer": "lending"
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "Neither Rema nor his friends ___ guilty.",
    "options": [
      "is",
      "has been found",
      "have been found",
      "was found"
    ],
    "answer": "have been found"
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "He said that he ------ abroad last month .",
    "options": [
      "had been to",
      "had been in",
      "went to",
      "would have gone"
    ],
    "answer": "had been to"
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "The new policy will _ significant changes to our operations.",
    "options": [
      "bring over",
      "bring up",
      "bring forward",
      "bring about"
    ],
    "answer": "bring about"
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "The speaker is admired _ his eloquence and clarity.",
    "options": [
      "for both",
      "to both",
      "in both",
      "by both"
    ],
    "answer": "for both"
  },
  {
    "id": 51,
    "question": "A critic rebuked the author _ the introduction for clarity.",
    "options": [
      "to revise",
      "revising",
      "revise",
      "revised"
    ],
    "answer": "to revise"
  },
  {
    "id": 52,
    "question": "A comparison using \"like\" or \"as\" is called a/an—",
    "options": [
      "Proverb",
      "Simile",
      "Idiom",
      "Metaphor"
    ],
    "answer": "Simile"
  },
  {
    "id": 53,
    "question": "What is the noun form of \"creative\"?",
    "options": [
      "Creativeness",
      "Create",
      "Creatively",
      "Creating"
    ],
    "answer": "Creativeness"
  },
  {
    "id": 54,
    "question": "Which is the adverb form of \"efficient\"?",
    "options": [
      "Efficiency",
      "Efficiently",
      "Efficienciness",
      "Efficience"
    ],
    "answer": "Efficiently"
  },
  {
    "id": 55,
    "question": "Choose the correct sentence",
    "options": [
      "Where have you been born?",
      "Where had you been born?",
      "Where were you born?",
      "Where was your birth?"
    ],
    "answer": "Where were you born?"
  },
  {
    "id": 56,
    "question": "Choose the correct sentence",
    "options": [
      "What are your parent?",
      "What does your parent do?",
      "What is your parents?",
      "What do your parent do?"
    ],
    "answer": "What does your parent do?"
  },
  {
    "id": 57,
    "question": "What is the antonym of 'vicissitude'?",
    "options": [
      "change",
      "hardship",
      "fluctuation",
      "stability"
    ],
    "answer": "stability"
  },
  {
    "id": 58,
    "question": "What is the synonym of 'ponder'?",
    "options": [
      "ignore",
      "Wonder",
      "Think deeply",
      "Act quickly"
    ],
    "answer": "Think deeply"
  },
  {
    "id": 59,
    "question": "Which one is the correct spelling?",
    "options": [
      "Manuever",
      "Manover",
      "Manuevere",
      "Manoeuvre"
    ],
    "answer": "Manoeuvre"
  },
  {
    "id": 60,
    "question": "To \"keep someone at arm's length\" means to",
    "options": [
      "keep someone close and trusted",
      "physically push someone away",
      "hug someone warmly",
      "maintain distance or avoid close relationship"
    ],
    "answer": "maintain distance or avoid close relationship"
  },
  {
    "id": 61,
    "question": "A short saying that expresses a general truth is a ------.",
    "options": [
      "simile",
      "idiom",
      "proverb",
      "metaphor"
    ],
    "answer": "proverb"
  },
  {
    "id": 62,
    "question": "He tried to explain it, but I couldn't make _ of it.",
    "options": [
      "pieces and bits",
      "meaningful",
      "cuts and corners",
      "head or tail"
    ],
    "answer": "head or tail"
  },
  {
    "id": 63,
    "question": "What does the phrase \"heat one's brain out\" mean?",
    "options": [
      "To physically hurt someone",
      "To memorize something quickly",
      "To act sensibly",
      "To think very hard about something"
    ],
    "answer": "To think very hard about something"
  },
  {
    "id": 64,
    "question": "The meaning of the phrase Daisy Dukes",
    "options": [
      "important",
      "shorts",
      "soft",
      "delicate"
    ],
    "answer": "shorts"
  },
  {
    "id": 65,
    "question": "Choose the word that is correctly spelt:",
    "options": [
      "Ridiculous",
      "Rediculous",
      "Ridiculus",
      "Ridiculas"
    ],
    "answer": "Ridiculous"
  },
  {
    "id": 66,
    "question": "Choose the word that is correctly spelt:",
    "options": [
      "Precinct",
      "Prensict",
      "Prensinct",
      "Preinct"
    ],
    "answer": "Precinct"
  },
  {
    "id": 67,
    "question": "Call it a day",
    "options": [
      "Start working",
      "Finish working",
      "Take a break",
      "Work overtime"
    ],
    "answer": "Finish working"
  },
  {
    "id": 68,
    "question": "Elephant in the room",
    "options": [
      "Large company",
      "Big investment",
      "Obvious issue",
      "Negotiation"
    ],
    "answer": "Obvious issue"
  },
  {
    "id": 69,
    "question": "After several delays, the company finally managed to _ the merger last week.",
    "options": [
      "bring about",
      "bring over",
      "bring up",
      "bring in"
    ],
    "answer": "bring about"
  },
  {
    "id": 70,
    "question": "He takes pride _ his meticulous attention to detail, even when no one notices.",
    "options": [
      "at",
      "for",
      "in",
      "with"
    ],
    "answer": "in"
  },
  {
    "id": 71,
    "question": "What is the noun form of \"beautiful\"?",
    "options": [
      "Beautifly",
      "Beautifully",
      "Beautifying",
      "Beauty"
    ],
    "answer": "Beauty"
  },
  {
    "id": 72,
    "question": "They made her _ the entire proposal again from scratch.",
    "options": [
      "to rewrite",
      "rewriting",
      "rewrite",
      "rewritten"
    ],
    "answer": "rewrite"
  },
  {
    "id": 73,
    "question": "Find the synonym of the word: PERPETUAL",
    "options": [
      "Immortal",
      "Fatal",
      "Consistence",
      "Adhesion"
    ],
    "answer": "Immortal"
  },
  {
    "id": 74,
    "question": "Find the synonym of the word ‘Hypothesis’?",
    "options": [
      "Proof",
      "Quality",
      "Supposition",
      "Promotion"
    ],
    "answer": "Supposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 75,
    "question": "The antonym of the word 'Prodigal' is—",
    "options": [
      "Thrifty",
      "Peculiar",
      "Amity",
      "Strange"
    ],
    "answer": "Thrifty"
  },
  {
    "id": 76,
    "question": "The antonym of the word 'delicious' is—",
    "options": [
      "appetizing",
      "scrumptious",
      "displeasing",
      "dainty"
    ],
    "answer": "displeasing"
  },
  {
    "id": 77,
    "question": "Choose the word that is spelled correctly-",
    "options": [
      "Bureacracy",
      "Bereaucracy",
      "Buercracy",
      "Bureaucracy"
    ],
    "answer": "Bureaucracy"
  },
  {
    "id": 78,
    "question": "Choose the word that is spelled correctly-",
    "options": [
      "Diphtheria",
      "Diptheria",
      "Deptheria",
      "Dephtheria"
    ],
    "answer": "Diphtheria"
  },
  {
    "id": 79,
    "question": "Your conduct admits ----- no excuse.",
    "options": [
      "to",
      "for",
      "of",
      "at"
    ],
    "answer": "of"
  },
  {
    "id": 80,
    "question": "Data is the plural form of which one",
    "options": [
      "Dative",
      "Datu",
      "Datum",
      "Datas"
    ],
    "answer": "Datum"
  },
  {
    "id": 81,
    "question": "Which one is singular",
    "options": [
      "Agenda",
      "Hypothesis",
      "Media",
      "Syllabi"
    ],
    "answer": "Hypothesis"
  },
  {
    "id": 82,
    "question": "Which one of the following is a feminine gender?",
    "options": [
      "Chairman",
      "hen",
      "book",
      "table"
    ],
    "answer": "hen"
  },
  {
    "id": 83,
    "question": "Money or property brought by a woman to her husband at marriage",
    "options": [
      "Ornament",
      "Honorary",
      "Adornment",
      "Dowry"
    ],
    "answer": "Dowry"
  },
  {
    "id": 84,
    "question": "The man --- malaria.",
    "options": [
      "died of",
      "died off",
      "died from",
      "died by"
    ],
    "answer": "died of"
  },
  {
    "id": 85,
    "question": "The girl ----- be innocent",
    "options": [
      "appeared into",
      "appeared to",
      "Accused to",
      "appeared as"
    ],
    "answer": "appeared to"
  },
  {
    "id": 86,
    "question": "I --- you on this point.",
    "options": [
      "different from",
      "different with",
      "indifferent to",
      "differ with"
    ],
    "answer": "differ with"
  },
  {
    "id": 87,
    "question": "After breakfast, she --- in the park",
    "options": [
      "walked about",
      "walked through",
      "walked along",
      "walk along"
    ],
    "answer": "walked along"
  },
  {
    "id": 88,
    "question": "Students should --- the rule.",
    "options": [
      "aim at",
      "abide by",
      "bask in",
      "cohort in"
    ],
    "answer": "abide by"
  },
  {
    "id": 89,
    "question": "What is the antonym of Audacious",
    "options": [
      "Bold",
      "Timid",
      "Fearless",
      "Daring"
    ],
    "answer": "Timid"
  },
  {
    "id": 90,
    "question": "What is the antonym of Frivolous",
    "options": [
      "Serious",
      "Trivial",
      "Fun",
      "Silly"
    ],
    "answer": "Serious"
  },
  {
    "id": 91,
    "question": "What is the antonym of Contrite",
    "options": [
      "Angry",
      "Protracted",
      "Unrepentant",
      "Surfeit"
    ],
    "answer": "Unrepentant"
  },
  {
    "id": 92,
    "question": "What is the antonym of Mollify",
    "options": [
      "Stultify",
      "Infuriate",
      "Placate",
      "Squander"
    ],
    "answer": "Infuriate"
  },
  {
    "id": 93,
    "question": "What is the antonym of Innocuous",
    "options": [
      "Harmless",
      "Dangerous",
      "Insignificant",
      "Gentle"
    ],
    "answer": "Dangerous"
  },
  {
    "id": 94,
    "question": "What is the synonym of Ubiquitous",
    "options": [
      "Rare",
      "Widespread",
      "Local",
      "Invisible"
    ],
    "answer": "Widespread"
  },
  {
    "id": 95,
    "question": "What is the synonym of Perfunctory",
    "options": [
      "Thorough",
      "Superficial",
      "Passionate",
      "Careful"
    ],
    "answer": "Superficial"
  },
  {
    "id": 96,
    "question": "What is the synonym of Ameliorate",
    "options": [
      "Worsen",
      "Improve",
      "Neglect",
      "Reject"
    ],
    "answer": "Improve"
  },
  {
    "id": 97,
    "question": "What is the synonym of Auspicious",
    "options": [
      "Inauspicious",
      "Prolific",
      "Propitious",
      "Dubious"
    ],
    "answer": "Propitious"
  },
  {
    "id": 98,
    "question": "What is the synonym of Jingoism",
    "options": [
      "Nepotism",
      "Altruism",
      "Chauvinism",
      "Solecism"
    ],
    "answer": "Chauvinism"
  },
  {
    "id": 99,
    "question": "Highly attractive and able to arouses hope and desire",
    "options": [
      "Alluring",
      "Elusiveness",
      "Tenacity",
      "Knotty"
    ],
    "answer": "Alluring"
  },
  {
    "id": 100,
    "question": "The right and power to interpret and apply the law",
    "options": [
      "Nugatory",
      "Jurisdiction",
      "Lawrence",
      "Judiciary"
    ],
    "answer": "Jurisdiction"
  },
  {
    "id": 101,
    "question": "An act of mass destruction and loss of life",
    "options": [
      "Oregon",
      "Cannibal",
      "Holocaust",
      "Homicide"
    ],
    "answer": "Holocaust"
  },
  {
    "id": 102,
    "question": "A person with the same name as another",
    "options": [
      "Nickname",
      "Namesake",
      "Anonymous",
      "Pseudonym"
    ],
    "answer": "Namesake"
  },
  {
    "id": 103,
    "question": "Identify the common gender:",
    "options": [
      "Mentrix",
      "Doe",
      "Gander",
      "Cousin"
    ],
    "answer": "Cousin"
  },
  {
    "id": 104,
    "question": "Identify the correct spelling:",
    "options": [
      "reconnaisance",
      "reconnoissance",
      "reconnaissance",
      "reconnaissence"
    ],
    "answer": "reconnaissance"
  },
  {
    "id": 105,
    "question": "The verb form of the word 'amusement' is—",
    "options": [
      "amuse",
      "amusing",
      "amused",
      "amusingly"
    ],
    "answer": "amuse"
  },
  {
    "id": 106,
    "question": "My brother is an elderly person. Here 'elderly' is—",
    "options": [
      "noun",
      "adverb",
      "adjective",
      "conjunction"
    ],
    "answer": "adjective"
  },
  {
    "id": 107,
    "question": "Identify the word having the same form in both singular and plural:",
    "options": [
      "craft",
      "hunk",
      "hunk",
      "moose"
    ],
    "answer": "moose"
  },
  {
    "id": 108,
    "question": "Fill in the blank with the appropriate article: The mother seized — boy by the collar.",
    "options": [
      "the",
      "a",
      "an",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "the"
  },
  {
    "id": 109,
    "question": "The moon goes round the earth. In this sentence ‘round’ is a/an—",
    "options": [
      "conjunction",
      "preposition",
      "adjective",
      "adverb"
    ],
    "answer": "preposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 110,
    "question": "The suffix ‘hood’ can be added to—",
    "options": [
      "friend",
      "honest",
      "parent",
      "wide"
    ],
    "answer": "parent"
  },
  {
    "id": 111,
    "question": "What does 'take someone to task' mean?",
    "options": [
      "to scold someone",
      "to give someone an activity",
      "to praise someone",
      "to take revenge on someone"
    ],
    "answer": "to scold someone"
  },
  {
    "id": 112,
    "question": "What is the synonym of 'lament'?",
    "options": [
      "Delight",
      "Bemoan",
      "Exult",
      "Rejoice"
    ],
    "answer": "Bemoan"
  },
  {
    "id": 113,
    "question": "If you dilly-dally, you __.",
    "options": [
      "do your work diligently",
      "do your work slowly",
      "hesitate to do your work",
      "do your work quickly"
    ],
    "answer": "do your work slowly"
  },
  {
    "id": 114,
    "question": "There is a breakthrough in the negotiation between the rebel group and the government. What is the meaning of 'breakthrough' here?",
    "options": [
      "an important development",
      "an interval",
      "a deadline",
      "an interruption"
    ],
    "answer": "an important development"
  },
  {
    "id": 115,
    "question": "What does 'rule of thumb' mean?",
    "options": [
      "To complain with angry emotion",
      "To give approval",
      "To measure something",
      "A general guidance and making a decision"
    ],
    "answer": "A general guidance and making a decision"
  },
  {
    "id": 116,
    "question": "There is a strong friendship ___ Taskin and Naziha.",
    "options": [
      "within",
      "between",
      "with",
      "in"
    ],
    "answer": "between"
  },
  {
    "id": 117,
    "question": "Which word is plural?",
    "options": [
      "Criteria",
      "Index",
      "Analysis",
      "Crisis"
    ],
    "answer": "Criteria"
  },
  {
    "id": 118,
    "question": "What is the antonym of 'sacred'?",
    "options": [
      "Inviolable",
      "Exempt",
      "Blasphemous",
      "Pure"
    ],
    "answer": "Blasphemous"
  },
  {
    "id": 119,
    "question": "Identify the synonym of 'Denial':",
    "options": [
      "rebuff",
      "refusal",
      "rebuttal",
      "refuge"
    ],
    "answer": "refusal"
  },
  {
    "id": 120,
    "question": "The word 'decadent' means",
    "options": [
      "rotten",
      "morally declined",
      "dissident",
      "defiant"
    ],
    "answer": "morally declined"
  },
  {
    "id": 121,
    "question": "Select the antonym for Generous",
    "options": [
      "cruel",
      "harsh",
      "friendly",
      "stingy"
    ],
    "answer": "stingy"
  },
  {
    "id": 122,
    "question": "Blockade এর বাংলা পারিভাষিক শব্দ কোনটি",
    "options": [
      "বন্ধন",
      "অবরোধ",
      "চাপ",
      "আবর্ত"
    ],
    "answer": "অবরোধ"
  },
  {
    "id": 123,
    "question": "The idiom cry over spilled milk means—",
    "options": [
      "to be upset about something irretrievably lost",
      "to cry incessantly",
      "to cry for a dead pet",
      "to cry for urgent help"
    ],
    "answer": "to be upset about something irretrievably lost"
  },
  {
    "id": 124,
    "question": "The idiom 'carry on with' means—",
    "options": [
      "to progress carefully",
      "to progress fast",
      "to continue",
      "to progress gradually"
    ],
    "answer": "to continue"
  },
  {
    "id": 125,
    "question": "The word biophilia means—",
    "options": [
      "relating to biology",
      "human tendency to connect with nature",
      "study of nature",
      "biological"
    ],
    "answer": "human tendency to connect with nature"
  },
  {
    "id": 126,
    "question": "Fill in the blank with the appropriate preposition: Rina does not excel — English.",
    "options": [
      "at",
      "to",
      "for",
      "of"
    ],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 127,
    "question": "Choose the synonym for \"fright\":",
    "options": [
      "Pusillanimity",
      "Composure",
      "Apprehension",
      "Equanimity"
    ],
    "answer": "Apprehension"
  },
  {
    "id": 128,
    "question": "A person who leaves his/her own country to settle permanently in another is called a/an",
    "options": [
      "immigrant",
      "expatriate",
      "emigrant",
      "migrant"
    ],
    "answer": "emigrant"
  },
  {
    "id": 129,
    "question": "“The icing on the cake” means —",
    "options": [
      "a slice of the cake",
      "an attractive but unnecessary addition",
      "an attractive service",
      "an attractive and essential enhancement"
    ],
    "answer": "an attractive but unnecessary addition"
  },
  {
    "id": 130,
    "question": "Selina knocked it ------ the park with her performance in culinary arts.",
    "options": [
      "outside",
      "out of",
      "inside",
      "off"
    ],
    "answer": "out of"
  },
  {
    "id": 131,
    "question": "She’s mad— me for being late.",
    "options": [
      "to",
      "towards",
      "at",
      "against"
    ],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 132,
    "question": "Which of the following words has two plural forms?",
    "options": [
      "father",
      "mother",
      "sister",
      "brother"
    ],
    "answer": "brother"
  },
  {
    "id": 133,
    "question": "Complete the following proverb: Fools rush in where—",
    "options": [
      "angels fear to tread",
      "every angel fears to tread",
      "angels fear to tread",
      "all angels fear to tread"
    ],
    "answer": "angels fear to tread"
  },
  {
    "id": 134,
    "question": "Intellectual montage is / an—",
    "options": [
      "mental condition",
      "film editing technique that juxtaposes contrasting images",
      "philosophical terminology",
      "alternative term for a flashback"
    ],
    "answer": "film editing technique that juxtaposes contrasting images"
  },
  {
    "id": 135,
    "question": "The noun form of “replete” is—",
    "options": [
      "repletation",
      "repletance",
      "replecacy",
      "repletion"
    ],
    "answer": "repletion"
  },
  {
    "id": 136,
    "question": "Come on, it's time to go home. Here “home” is / an—",
    "options": [
      "noun",
      "adjective",
      "adverb",
      "verb"
    ],
    "answer": "adverb"
  },
  {
    "id": 137,
    "question": "Glossary শব্দের বাংলা পরিভাষা",
    "options": [
      "জ্ঞানপত্র",
      "সর্বসাকল্যে",
      "গুদামজাত",
      "শব্দার্থপঞ্জি"
    ],
    "answer": "শব্দার্থপঞ্জি"
  },
  {
    "id": 138,
    "question": "Which one has the identical singular and plural form?",
    "options": [
      "Memorandum",
      "Stimulus",
      "Dice",
      "Oasis"
    ],
    "answer": "Dice"
  },
  {
    "id": 139,
    "question": "Fill in the blank with the appropriate preposition: \"She was married _ a rich man.\"",
    "options": [
      "with",
      "to",
      "of",
      "off"
    ],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 140,
    "question": "Which gender is the word 'sibling'?",
    "options": [
      "Masculine",
      "Feminine",
      "Neuter",
      "Common"
    ],
    "answer": "Common"
  },
  {
    "id": 141,
    "question": "Find out the correctly spelt word:",
    "options": [
      "reminiscence",
      "reminescence",
      "reminiscence",
      "remaniscence"
    ],
    "answer": "reminiscence"
  },
  {
    "id": 142,
    "question": "\"It was a cowardly attack on a defenceless man.\" Here 'cowardly' is a—",
    "options": [
      "adverb",
      "adjective",
      "noun",
      "conjunction"
    ],
    "answer": "adjective"
  },
  {
    "id": 143,
    "question": "\"The river flows past the village.\" Here 'past' is a/an—",
    "options": [
      "noun",
      "verb",
      "adverb",
      "preposition"
    ],
    "answer": "preposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 144,
    "question": "The synonym of the word 'doleful' is—",
    "options": [
      "playful",
      "cheerful",
      "mournful",
      "deceitful"
    ],
    "answer": "mournful"
  },
  {
    "id": 145,
    "question": "The antonym of the word 'Sanguine' is—",
    "options": [
      "hopeful",
      "sarcastic",
      "angry",
      "pessimistic"
    ],
    "answer": "pessimistic"
  },
  {
    "id": 146,
    "question": "Choose the correct spelling.",
    "options": [
      "connoisseur",
      "cosiseur",
      "connaisure",
      "connisure"
    ],
    "answer": "connoisseur"
  },
  {
    "id": 147,
    "question": "I bumped — one of my school teachers at New Market yesterday.",
    "options": [
      "with",
      "into",
      "against",
      "to"
    ],
    "answer": "into"
  },
  {
    "id": 148,
    "question": "The past form of the verb 'beat' is—",
    "options": [
      "beater",
      "beat",
      "bit",
      "bite"
    ],
    "answer": "beat"
  },
  {
    "id": 149,
    "question": "Which of the following is in singular form?",
    "options": [
      "hypotheses",
      "radius",
      "formulae",
      "syllabi"
    ],
    "answer": "radius"
  },
  {
    "id": 150,
    "question": "What is the feminine gender of 'Sheep'?",
    "options": [
      "more",
      "ewe",
      "doe",
      "cow"
    ],
    "answer": "ewe"
  },
  {
    "id": 151,
    "question": "What is the meaning of 'out and out'—",
    "options": [
      "not at all",
      "through",
      "thoroughly",
      "outside"
    ],
    "answer": "thoroughly"
  },
  {
    "id": 152,
    "question": "Choose the correct antonym of the word “macho”:",
    "options": [
      "arrogant",
      "haughty",
      "modest",
      "machismo"
    ],
    "answer": "modest"
  },
  {
    "id": 153,
    "question": "Which of the following is a synonym of “diminutive”?",
    "options": [
      "petite",
      "short",
      "large",
      "pigmy"
    ],
    "answer": "petite"
  },
  {
    "id": 154,
    "question": "The “green-eyed monster” means—",
    "options": [
      "danger",
      "hatred",
      "envy",
      "jealousy"
    ],
    "answer": "jealousy"
  },
  {
    "id": 155,
    "question": "Ethics শব্দের সঠিক পারিভাষিক শব্দ কোনটি",
    "options": [
      "তথ্যচিত্র",
      "ব্রতকথা",
      "তথ্যকথা",
      "নীতিশাস্ত্র"
    ],
    "answer": "নীতিশাস্ত্র"
  },
  {
    "id": 156,
    "question": "Which one is the correct spelling?",
    "options": [
      "assasination",
      "aquarium",
      "armatur",
      "assylum"
    ],
    "answer": "aquarium"
  },
  {
    "id": 157,
    "question": "“A way of speaking or writing that makes something sound better or more exciting than it really is.” — this can be the best definition of—",
    "options": [
      "oxymoron",
      "synecdoche",
      "sarcasm",
      "hyperbole"
    ],
    "answer": "hyperbole"
  },
  {
    "id": 158,
    "question": "Macbeth killed the king. He was arrested on the charge of—",
    "options": [
      "patricide",
      "regicide",
      "fratricide",
      "homicide"
    ],
    "answer": "regicide"
  },
  {
    "id": 159,
    "question": "What is the meaning of ‘French leave’?",
    "options": [
      "Leave no holiday",
      "Spending time in France",
      "Leave without permission",
      "Emergence Leave"
    ],
    "answer": "Leave without permission"
  },
  {
    "id": 160,
    "question": "The synonym of the word ‘spectacular’ is",
    "options": [
      "ugly",
      "Spacious",
      "Breathtaking",
      "spatial"
    ],
    "answer": "Breathtaking"
  },
  {
    "id": 161,
    "question": "Transparency শব্দের বাংলা পরিভাষা কী?",
    "options": [
      "যথার্থতা",
      "নির্ভরযোগ্যতা",
      "স্বচ্ছতা",
      "দুর্নীতিদমন"
    ],
    "answer": "স্বচ্ছতা"
  },
  {
    "id": 162,
    "question": "What does the idiom “take someone to task” mean?",
    "options": [
      "To give someone a task to do",
      "To praise someone for his task",
      "To rebuke someone",
      "To appoint someone"
    ],
    "answer": "To rebuke someone"
  },
  {
    "id": 163,
    "question": "Choose the correct spelling",
    "options": [
      "Repeatition",
      "Repeatation",
      "Repetition",
      "Ripiatition"
    ],
    "answer": "Repetition"
  },
  {
    "id": 164,
    "question": "কোনটি অশুদ্ধ বানান?",
    "options": [
      "Pneumonia",
      "Dyspepsia",
      "Gastitis",
      "Diarrhea"
    ],
    "answer": "Gastitis"
  },
  {
    "id": 165,
    "question": "Do you know the solution ---- the problem?",
    "options": [
      "of",
      "for",
      "to",
      "about"
    ],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 166,
    "question": "She succeeded ---- her good work.",
    "options": [
      "because",
      "since",
      "because of",
      "as"
    ],
    "answer": "because of"
  },
  {
    "id": 167,
    "question": "She works hard. What part of speech is the underlined word.",
    "options": [
      "Adjective",
      "Adverb",
      "Verb",
      "Noun"
    ],
    "answer": "Adverb"
  },
  {
    "id": 168,
    "question": "A speech made without any previous thought, preparation or practice is called a/an—",
    "options": [
      "free speech",
      "extempore speech",
      "maiden speech",
      "rousing speech"
    ],
    "answer": "extempore speech"
  },
  {
    "id": 169,
    "question": "Choose the antonym of ‘controversy’:",
    "options": [
      "contention",
      "bickering",
      "unanimity",
      "dispute"
    ],
    "answer": "unanimity"
  },
  {
    "id": 170,
    "question": "Select the synonym for ‘inclement’:",
    "options": [
      "affable",
      "mild",
      "rough",
      "genial"
    ],
    "answer": "rough"
  },
  {
    "id": 171,
    "question": "The idiom 'smell a rat' means to—",
    "options": [
      "detect bad smell",
      "be in a bad mood",
      "suspect something wrong",
      "see hidden meaning"
    ],
    "answer": "suspect something wrong"
  },
  {
    "id": 172,
    "question": "The prefix 'non' can be added to—",
    "options": [
      "office",
      "regular",
      "partisan",
      "obey"
    ],
    "answer": "regular"
  },
  {
    "id": 173,
    "question": "Pick the correct spelt word —",
    "options": [
      "Conscientious",
      "Consientious",
      "Concientious",
      "Conscientious"
    ],
    "answer": "Conscientious"
  },
  {
    "id": 174,
    "question": "We work every day except Friday. In this sentence “except” is an —",
    "options": [
      "Adjective",
      "Noun",
      "Preposition",
      "Pronoun"
    ],
    "answer": "Preposition"
  },
  {
    "id": 175,
    "question": "Which of the following is the correct feminine form of “neighbour”?",
    "options": [
      "Masculin",
      "Feminine",
      "Neuter",
      "Common"
    ],
    "answer": "Common"
  },
  {
    "id": 176,
    "question": "Identify the word that can be used as both singular and plural —",
    "options": [
      "Light",
      "Shot",
      "Criterion",
      "Cannon"
    ],
    "answer": "Cannon"
  },
  {
    "id": 177,
    "question": "“After lunch we went for a leisurely stroll.” Here “leisurely” is an —",
    "options": [
      "adverb",
      "Adjective",
      "Noun",
      "conjunction"
    ],
    "answer": "Adjective"
  },
  {
    "id": 178,
    "question": "Which sentence is correct?",
    "options": [
      "The picture was hanged on the wall.",
      "The picture was hung on the wall.",
      "The picture was hunged on the wall.",
      "The picture had hanged on the wall."
    ],
    "answer": "The picture was hung on the wall."
  },
  {
    "id": 179,
    "question": "The correct spelling is —.",
    "options": [
      "Examplary",
      "Exemplary",
      "Exemplery",
      "Examplery"
    ],
    "answer": "Exemplary"
  },
  {
    "id": 180,
    "question": "Which one is the feminine gender of ‘horse’.",
    "options": [
      "Hind",
      "Doe",
      "Mare",
      "Vixen"
    ],
    "answer": "Mare"
  },
  {
    "id": 181,
    "question": "Plural form of the word Appendix is",
    "options": [
      "Appendixes",
      "Appendises",
      "Appendices",
      "Appendrics"
    ],
    "answer": "Appendices"
  },
  {
    "id": 182,
    "question": "Which one is in plural number?",
    "options": [
      "data",
      "basis",
      "goose",
      "formula"
    ],
    "answer": "data"
  },
  {
    "id": 183,
    "question": "If a substance is cohesive, it tends to-.",
    "options": [
      "bend without much difficulty",
      "retain heat",
      "stick together",
      "break easily"
    ],
    "answer": "stick together"
  },
  {
    "id": 184,
    "question": "The opposite of \"admit\" is to...",
    "options": [
      "defy",
      "deny",
      "doubt",
      "accept"
    ],
    "answer": "deny"
  },
  {
    "id": 185,
    "question": "The word 'Tiny' means:",
    "options": [
      "small",
      "thin",
      "strong",
      "tall"
    ],
    "answer": "small"
  },
  {
    "id": 186,
    "question": "The word 'essential' means:",
    "options": [
      "very clear",
      "very important",
      "very new",
      "very difficult"
    ],
    "answer": "very important"
  },
  {
    "id": 187,
    "question": "It had been raining _ three days.",
    "options": [
      "of",
      "from",
      "for",
      "on"
    ],
    "answer": "for"
  },
  {
    "id": 188,
    "question": "...Friday evening, I saw him.",
    "options": [
      "in",
      "at",
      "of",
      "from"
    ],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 189,
    "question": "Turn right ---- the traffic light",
    "options": [
      "on",
      "at",
      "in",
      "over"
    ],
    "answer": "at"
  },
  {
    "id": 190,
    "question": "I went... the kitchen to make dinner.",
    "options": [
      "on",
      "from",
      "of",
      "in"
    ],
    "answer": "in"
  },
  {
    "id": 191,
    "question": "Mainamati flows... Cumilla and Dhaka.",
    "options": [
      "by",
      "between",
      "beyond",
      "beside"
    ],
    "answer": "between"
  },
  {
    "id": 192,
    "question": "He goes home --- foot.",
    "options": [
      "with",
      "on",
      "to",
      "by"
    ],
    "answer": "on"
  },
  {
    "id": 193,
    "question": "The books are ----- the table.",
    "options": [
      "on",
      "above",
      "from",
      "in"
    ],
    "answer": "on"
  },
  {
    "id": 194,
    "question": "It has been raining --- two hours.",
    "options": [
      "of",
      "about",
      "between",
      "for"
    ],
    "answer": "for"
  },
  {
    "id": 195,
    "question": "Many young people died --- the nation.",
    "options": [
      "of",
      "by",
      "in",
      "for"
    ],
    "answer": "for"
  },
  {
    "id": 196,
    "question": "It has been raining --- two hours.",
    "options": [
      "of",
      "about",
      "between",
      "for"
    ],
    "answer": "for"
  },
  {
    "id": 197,
    "question": "A man of character is true --- his word.",
    "options": [
      "in",
      "on",
      "to",
      "at"
    ],
    "answer": "to"
  },
  {
    "id": 198,
    "question": "Identify the correct spelling",
    "options": [
      "surveillance",
      "survaillance",
      "survuillence",
      "survillance"
    ],
    "answer": "surveillance"
  },
  {
    "id": 199,
    "question": "Which one of following is correct?",
    "options": [
      "Adolescence",
      "Addolescence",
      "Adolescense",
      "Adollescence"
    ],
    "answer": "Adolescence"
  },
  {
    "id": 200,
    "question": "Which of the following spelling is correct?",
    "options": [
      "Privilege",
      "Previlege",
      "Privilige",
      "Prevelege"
    ],
    "answer": "Privilege"
  },
  {
    "id": 201,
    "question": "Which one of the following is the opposite word of gentle?",
    "options": [
      "Decent",
      "Modest",
      "Rude",
      "Bad"
    ],
    "answer": "Rude"
  },
  {
    "id": 202,
    "question": "‘Cut up’ means",
    "options": [
      "discount",
      "reduce",
      "dislocate",
      "separate"
    ],
    "answer": "separate"
  },
  {
    "id": 203,
    "question": "What is the antonym of the word ‘contaminate’",
    "options": [
      "Sanctity",
      "Invigorate",
      "Taint",
      "Purity"
    ],
    "answer": "Purity"
  },
  {
    "id": 204,
    "question": "What is the antonym of 'conspicuous'?",
    "options": [
      "obscure",
      "conscious",
      "obvious",
      "remarkable"
    ],
    "answer": "obscure"
  },
  {
    "id": 205,
    "question": "'Lingua Franca' means the",
    "options": [
      "international language",
      "first language",
      "common language",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "answer": "common language"
  },
  {
    "id": 206,
    "question": "Meaning of the idiom 'Bottom line' is—",
    "options": [
      "The final step",
      "The end of a point",
      "The last line of the book",
      "The essential point"
    ],
    "answer": "The essential point"
  },
  {
    "id": 207,
    "question": "The phrase 'in black and white' means—",
    "options": [
      "in writing",
      "with black and white colour",
      "face to face",
      "combination of black and white"
    ],
    "answer": "in writing"
  },
  {
    "id": 208,
    "question": "He is the black sheep in the family. Here 'black sheep' means—",
    "options": [
      "a clever person",
      "an irritating person",
      "a noble persons",
      "an unworthy person"
    ],
    "answer": "an unworthy person"
  },
  {
    "id": 209,
    "question": "Choose the correct spelling:",
    "options": [
      "Repetation",
      "Repetation",
      "Repetation",
      "Repetition"
    ],
    "answer": "Repetition"
  },
  {
    "id": 210,
    "question": "The correct spelling is:",
    "options": [
      "Condem",
      "condem",
      "condemn",
      "condemne"
    ],
    "answer": "condemn"
  },
  {
    "id": 211,
    "question": "A society in one where many languages are spoken:",
    "options": [
      "unilateral",
      "multilateral",
      "unilingual",
      "multilingual"
    ],
    "answer": "multilingual"
  },
  {
    "id": 212,
    "question": "A violation of grammatical manners is called:",
    "options": [
      "Jargon",
      "Colloquial",
      "Slang",
      "Solecism"
    ],
    "answer": "Solecism"
  },
  {
    "id": 213,
    "question": "A museum is a good collection of...",
    "options": [
      "relics",
      "historical",
      "resource",
      "tourists"
    ],
    "answer": "relics"
  },
  {
    "id": 214,
    "question": "One learns to grow food by ---",
    "options": [
      "cultivation",
      "planning",
      "study",
      "dancing"
    ],
    "answer": "cultivation"
  }
]